Fushi was awakened by Tonari's voice
when she rushed to his aid.
（観察者）
とらわれの身となったフシは
駆けつけたトナリの声によって
目覚め
With it, he regained his freedom.
再び自由を取り戻した
Pioran, Tonari, and her
friends were released,
ピオランとトナリたちは解放され
and they finally made
their way off the island.
ついに島から脱出する
Alas, Fushi was captured
once again by Hayase.
しかしフシはハヤセによって
またもや捕らえられてしまった
♪～
～♪
That's it, that's it...
（トナリ）そのまま そのまま…
うまく入れよ
Go straight in.
I got word that the immortal is inside there.
不死身が
あの中にいるって情報は つかんだ
Now, if he'll just read my letter...
あとは
この手紙を読んでくれれば…
"Immortal,
“不死身へ”
turn into the mole and get inside here.
“モグラになって ここに入れ
トナリより”と
From Tonari."
There.
よし！
ん？　ハッ
Hey, what are you doing?!
（フシ）
おい 何やってるんだ お前？
Why aren't you on the boat?
船に乗ってたんじゃないのかよ
Immortal!
え？　不死身！
（トナリ）うう…
"Turn into the mole and get in here."
“モグラになって ここに入れ”
You came to help me?
まさか助けに来たのか？
Y-Yeah, I guess.
そ… そうだけど？
You know I'm immortal.
オレが不死身なの知ってるだろ？
Besides, that hole...
大体 あの穴
壁の石は手で取れるほどボロいし
The walls are so brittle, you can
pull them apart with your hands.
They weren't even half as high as
the wall I climbed to get to Pioran.
ピオランの所まで登った壁の
半分の高さもない
I could have stayed inside,
中にいてやっても よかったけど
but I got bored, so I dug a
hole in the side and came out.
退屈だから 横穴 掘って出てきた
ああ…
I thought you were on the boat.
お前 船に乗ったんじゃないのか？
Didn't you get your wish
of leaving the island?
島を出るって目的は
かなったんだろ？
Why'd you do this?
なんで こんなことをする？
I felt bad for you after you were
captured by that hag Hayase.
あ… あのハヤセとかいうブスに
捕らわれてる あんたを
哀れに思ったんだよ
There you go again.
また余計なことを…
So everything I did for you was for nothing.
オレの気遣いがムダじゃないか
What do you mean, "again"?!
余計とか言うな！
ここに来るの 苦労したんだぞ
It wasn't easy getting here, you know!
You don't get it, do you?
分かってないな
What happens if the Nokkers come here again?
今ノッカーが来たら
どうするんだ？
You've just given me more
things I have to protect.
守らなきゃいけないもの
増やしやがって
What're you protecting?
あん？　何を守るってんだよ！
You, obviously.
お前に決まってるだろ
え？
（フシ）ん？
（トナリ）ハッ
Y-You were the one who
got protected last time!
こ… この前 守ってもらったのは
あんたのほうだったろ
Oh... Oh ,yeah.
ああ… そうだったな
まあいいや
Whatever.
Anyway, what are you going to do now?
それで どうするんだ これから？
I'm leaving on a boat.
船で ここを出る
To Continue On
What's up? Get on.
（フシ）どうした？　早く乗れよ
The waves are too high.
There's a storm coming.
波が高い… 時化(しけ)が来る
Let's set out on another day.
今晩 出るのは やめとこう
I'll be here. Don't worry.
オレがいるから大丈夫だよ
"Don't worry," my ass.
何が大丈夫だ
Do you know how far it
is to the port in Zedan?
ゼダンの港まで
どれだけあると思ってんだ
We'll get tossed into the water
before we make it there.
向こうに着く前に
２人とも海へ放り出されるぞ
（激しい雨と雷の音）
Last time, we were attacked by the
Nokkers when you'd taken that form.
前は その姿のときに
ノッカーに襲われた
Be careful.
気をつけろよ
Yeah.
（フシ）ああ
Do you think the Nokkers know when
it's a good time for them to attack?
（トナリ）ノッカーって
襲うタイミングを選んで来てるのかね
Dunno.
（フシ）さあ
But it's all right.
でも大丈夫だ
I told the guy in black to let
me know when they're coming.
ヤツらが来たら知らせるよう
黒い男に言ってあるから
They just caught me off guard last time.
前はユダンしたんだ
The Nokkers come to take
your powers, don't they?
ノッカーって あんたを
無力化させるために来てんでしょ？
Yeah.
（フシ）うん…
Why, though?
何のためだ？
I don't know.
（フシ）分からないよ
The man in black says you were made for the
purpose of preserving everything, right?
あんたは万物を保存することが
目的で作られたって
黒い男は言うんだろ？
Why does everything need to be preserved?
なぜ保存しなきゃならないんだ？
Is the world going to be
destroyed or something?
世界が ぶっ壊れでもするのか？
Destroyed?
（フシ）壊れる？
There are a lot of ways all life could die,
whether it's in disasters or something else.
災害なり何なり
生き物が死に絶える
きっかけは たくさんある
He must be a pretty thoughtful guy if he
made you in preparation for that event.
そのときに備えて
お前を作ってたんだとしたら
相当 親切なヤツだな
Is he God or something?
神様か何かか？
What's a god?
カミサマって何？
God's the crazy guy who made us
and everything else in the world.
神は この世界や うちらを創った
ヤバいヤツだよ
He makes something out of nothing.
ゼロからイチを作るんだ
He's kind to good people
and harsh on bad people.
いい人には優しく
悪い人には厳しい
He's kinda like a parent.
親みたいな存在だよ
That guy isn't my parent.
あんなのは親じゃない
だから神じゃない
So he's not a god.
What is he, then? A demon?
じゃあ何だ？　悪魔か？
So are the Nokkers God's servants
who stop the demons' plans?
それならノッカーは
悪魔の計画を阻止する神の使いか？
The demons are people who oppose God.
悪魔ってのは
神と敵対するヤツのことだよ
And, like, say...
そんで…
あー たとえば…
They're people who get a
kick out of killing people.
人を殺して楽しくなっちゃう
ヤツらのことだな
Like my dad did.
あたしの父親みたいにね
え？　トナリのお父さんって
I thought your dad came here,
but never killed anyone.
ここには来たけど
殺してはいないんでしょ？
Sorry, I lied.
ごめん あたしウソついた
I did believe that he hadn't killed anyone.
確かに信じてたよ
父は殺してないって
But that was only at first.
でも それは最初だけ
When it turns out the person you
trust might have committed murder,
信用してた人が殺人を
犯してしまったかもしれないとき
you can't help but assume there
was a reason they had to.
そうさせた理由があるんだって
考えちゃうよね
I thought that, too.
あたしも考えたよ
That something must have
forced my dad to do it.
きっと父を追い込んだものが
あったんだって
But when my dad was the last one standing
in the tournament, he was laughing.
でも大会で１人残った父は
笑ってた
I didn't know how he could
laugh after killing people.
人を殺して なんで笑えるのって
思った
It wasn't because he was happy?
うれしかったんじゃないの？
He could become the island
leader, and he could save you.
島長になって
トナリを助けられるって
But that's when it crossed my mind...
でも あたしは
ここで こう思ってしまった
"Oh, this is how Dad killed Mom."
ああ お父さんは こんなふうに
お母さんを殺したんだって
I'm just guessing, but I think the
fact that your dad killed your mom
たぶんだけど…
お父さんが お母さんを
殺してしまったことと
and the way your dad killed in the
tournament were two different things.
大会で殺さなきゃいけなかった
ことは別の話だと思う
It's too late.
もう遅いよ
When her father died,
his daughter thought to herself:
父を信じられなくなった娘は
こう考えるようになった
"My father is a wife-killing lowlife."
私の父は妻殺しのクズ
Same with all of you island prisoners.
お前らも そうだ 島の囚人ども
All of you lowlifes deserve to die.
お前らみたいなクズは
みんな死んじまえ
You know how I feel, right?
あんたなら分かるでしょ
この気持ち？
I ought to be sick of this island
after all the killing I've seen here.
さんざん この島で殺しを見て
嫌気がさしてるはずなのにね
But I'm just the same as the rest of them.
結局あたしもヤツらと一緒なんだ
In my mind, I kill everyone I don't like.
心の中では
気にくわないヤツを殺してる
That's why I had the nerve to play God.
だから あんな神の
マネごとみたいなことができたんだ
I'm not sure these people
can make it outside.
こんなヤツが外で
ちゃんと やっていけるのかねえ
I think coming to this island
completely poisoned my heart.
この島に来て あたしは
すっかり毒に侵されてしまった
Sorry.
How are you supposed to
react to that, right?
ごめん！
こんなこと聞かされても困るよな
もう寝よ！
Let's get some sleep.
フゥ…
Tonari, our parents might be demons,
トナリ オレたちの親は
悪魔かもしれない
but regardless of that,
we still do what we want to do.
だけど そんなの関係なく
やりたいことは やる
Isn't that right?
そうだろ？
You're right.
そうだね
Also, thanks for coming to save me.
あと… 助けに来てくれて
ありがとう
フフ…
（２人の寝息）
That night, I had a dream.
（トナリ）その夜 夢を見た
Hey, I'm home!
ただいま！　帰ったよ
Welcome home, Tonari.
（トナリの母）おかえり トナリ
Read this, Mom! It's my new book!
（トナリ）読んで お母さん 新作！
Let's see.
（トナリの母）どれどれ…
It's Tonari's masterpiece.
（トナリの父）トナリの力作だぞ
（３人の笑い声）
I decided I probably needed to
come up with a new dream.
（トナリ）たぶん もう新しい夢を
描かなきゃいけないんだと思った
Let's see...
そうだな…
This is what the future will look like.
きっと こんな未来だ
（トナリ）フッ…
Morning.
おはよ 出発しよ
Let's set out.
He's not here.
（従者Ａ）いませんねえ…
This is bad... What should
we tell Hayase-sama?
（従者Ｂ）マズいな…
ハヤセ様に どう言い訳しよう？
Well? How is Fushi?
（ハヤセ）どうだ フシの様子は？
（従者たち）うっ
（従者たちが言いよどむ声）
Hayase-sama!
（従者Ｃ）ハヤセ様！
The town...
街が… 街が大変です！
The town's in trouble!
All right, Immortal, let's go.
さあ不死身 行こう
What's wrong?
どうした？
The Nokkers have crawled up to the surface.
（観察者）ノッカーが地上に
這(は)い出(い)で街を襲っている
They're attacking the town.
Twenty minutes to the west.
ここから西へ20分
Sorry, Tonari,
（フシ）ごめん トナリ
オレ行かないと
I have to go.
Is it the Nokkers? Are they here?
まさかノッカーが来たのか？
Yeah.
ああ…
Ignore them!
（トナリ）無視しろよ！
救うべき人間は全員 救ってる
We've saved everyone who
deserves to be saved!
We just need to get out of here!
あとは ここを出るだけだ！
I'm worried about the islanders.
島の人たちが心配だ
Half of the people on this
island are criminals.
ここの島の半分は罪人
The other half are humans who
carry their tainted blood.
もう半分は その血を引いた
けがれた人間だ
If they still deserve to live,
それでも生きるに値するというなら
I'm sure God will see to it!
あんたの代わりに
神が生かしてくれるに違いない！
You can go without me, Tonari.
（フシ）
トナリ１人で出ていけばいい！
Immortal!
（トナリ）不死身！
You made the right choice.
（観察者）正しい判断だ
The Nokkers are formidable,
ノッカーは脅威だが
but they'll become even more troublesome
if you refuse to face them.
向き合うことをやめると
より厄介になる
Shut up.
うるさいな
さっさと居場所を教えろ
Just tell me where they are.
There's no reason to be so hasty.
（観察者）焦る必要はない
You won't need more than a single
sword to defeat the next enemy.
今度の敵は剣１本で済むだろう
おっ
Why aren't the Nokkers coming for me?
ノッカーは
なぜオレの所に来ない？
I don't know.
They may have plans of their own.
（観察者）さあ… 向こうにも
“考え”があるのかもな
Over there.
（従者）あそこです
They're rising from that
corpse pit over there.
あの死体置き場から
湧いているとのことです
What is rising, exactly?
（ハヤセ）
何が湧いているというのですか？
Wh-What the hell?!
（フシ）な… 何だよ これ…
（島民）ふっ
（島民）うっ
（島民）えいっ
（島民）ふっ
（島民）うっ
These are all Nokkers?
（フシ）これ 全部ノッカー？
I don't feel any of their pain.
（フシ）
痛みが全然 伝わってこない
Are they really Nokkers?
本当にノッカーなのか？
Everyone!
みんな！
あとはオレに任せて逃げろ！
Leave the rest to me and run!
（島民）おおっ 来てくれたのか
You came for us!
Shit! Why do they have to look like humans?
（フシ）クソッ なんで人間の姿
なんて してやがるんだ！
There's no reason to hesitate!
ためらうことはねえ
They came from the corpse pit!
こいつら 死体置き場から
出てきたんだ
Sorry.
ごめん！
ぐっ
You missed. Aim lower.
（観察者）ずれた もっと下だ
（フシ）うっ
ハッ
あっ く…
You aren't going by yourself, Immortal.
１人で行くなよ 不死身！
Tonari! Why did you come here?
トナリ！　なんで来た？
There's only one boat.
船は１つだ
あたしは あんたを連れて帰る
I'm taking you with me.
Behind you!
後ろ！
（トナリ）くっ
あっ
Are you all right, Tonari?
（ミァ）大丈夫 トナリ？
Man, it reeks here.
（ウーロイ）ここ くっせえ
Guys!
みんな！
Why...
（フシ）どうして？
Why did you come?!
なんで来たの？
That was such a lame line, Tonari.
（ミァ）トナリ そのセリフ
すっごくダサいよ
Two's better than one.
１人より２人
And even more will get the job done quicker.
２人より大勢のほうが
早く片づくでしょ
Right, Fushi-san?
ねっ フシさん？
Thanks, everyone.
ありがとう みんな…
But be careful.
でも気をつけて
They'll continue moving until you
destroy the core inside their bodies.
あいつらは 体の中にある核を
潰すまで動き続ける
Got it.
（サンデル）分かりました
Leave it to us!
俺たちに任せろ！
Let's do it.
（ウーパ）がんばる
We'll beat them all before the sun goes down!
（ウーロイ）日が落ちる前に
敵をぶっ倒してやるぜ！
Let's go, everyone!
いくぞ みんな！
（一同）おお！
おりゃあ！
ふんっ
（サンデル）ふんっ
（リガードの鳴き声）
How many more do you think there are?
あと どれくらい
いるんでしょうか？
Dunno. Until there are no
more corpses, I guess.
さあ… 死体がなくなるまでだな
Hundreds of people come to this island
every day, and hundreds more die.
この島では
毎日 数百人が仕入れられて
数百人が死んでいくからな
We'd better prepare ourselves.
覚悟したほうがいいぞ！
We're going to the corpse pit.
死体置き場に行く 援護して！
Give me cover.
Okay.
はい！
All right, let's go, everyone.
よし みんなで行こう
走って街を突っ切るぞ！
Run through the town!
（ウーロイたち）おお！
イタッ
あ…
ハッ
あっ…
（フシ）ん？
う…
あ… みんな…
Guys...
What's wrong?
（フシ）あ…
Oopa's missing!
（トナリ）どうした？
（ウーロイ）ウーパがいない！
（一同）あ…
She's on the ground.
Oopa!
（ミァ）転んでる… ウーパ！
Are you all right?
大丈夫？　さあ…
Let's go.
うっ あ… ああ…
ハッ
あ…
ああ…
ああっ…
They're underground.
（観察者）下にいる
Run, everyone!
逃げろ みんな！
（フシ）うっ く…
（ミァの痛みに同調する脈拍の音）
Black thing, tell me where it's safe!
（フシ）
黒いの！　安全な所を教えろ！
Run six minutes to the north.
（観察者）
ここから北へ６分 走れば
You'll be safe for three minutes there.
３分間は安全だ
（トナリの泣き声）
Mia!
Hang in there, Mia!
（トナリ）
ミァ しっかりして ミァ！
（ミァ）ハァ ハァ…
We have to stop the bleeding.
早く血を止めないと！
Give us something, Immortal!
何か出せ 不死身！
O-Okay.
（フシ）わ… 分かった
Maybe we can sew the wound shut with this.
これで傷口を縫えるかも
Can I pull this out, then?
じゃあ
こいつを抜いていいんだな？
Wait!
待って！　抜くと
余計 血が出て危険だって⸺
I read in a book that it can
make the bleeding even worse!
本で読んだことがある
What are we supposed to do, then?!
だったら どうすりゃいいんだよ！
I'm thinking!
考える！
考えるから ちょっと待ってよ
I'll think of something!
Just give me a minute!
We're going to lose Mia!
んなこと言ってる間にミァが…
Fushi-san, is there anything
else you could make?
フシさん もっと
ほかの物を出せませんか？
Anything else?
（フシ）ほかの物？
You can do something other
than make things, can't you?!
道具出す以外にも できるだろ？
Like heal wounds?
ケガを治すとか…
Please, Fushi, help us!
なあ フシ 助けてくれよ！
ミァが死んじまう
Mia's going to die!
Fushi!
フシ！
It's not as if I can do just anything.
（フシ）オレは…
何でも できるわけじゃない
I've never been able to save anyone.
人を助けられたことなんて…
Not even once.
一度も… ない！
Let's do it, everyone.
やりましょう 皆さん…
やるしかない
We have no choice.
（フシ）くっ…
Where are you going?
どこ行くんだ 不死身！
Immortal!
Oopa...
（ウーロイ）ウーパ…
Please, no, Immortal...
やめて 不死身…
殺さないで
Don't kill her.
She's already dead.
（フシ）もう死んでる
Mia!
（ウーロイ）ミァ！
ミァ…
ん… んん…
Why are you crying, Tonari?
なんで泣いてるの トナリ？
Because...
だって…
You're better off in life if you smile.
笑ってたほうが人生 得よ
I'm sorry, Mia.
ごめん ミァ あたしのせいだ
This is my fault.
P-Please don't say that, Tonari-san.
そ… そんなこと
言わないでください トナリさん
Where's Oopa?
ウーパは？
あっ あの子は…
She...
It's not her fault.
あいつは悪くないんだ
She...
中に… 中にノッカーが
She had the Nokkers inside her.
（ミァ）くっ
I know.
分かってる… 知ってるわ
I knew that.
（フシ）くっ
I'm sorry, Oopa.
ごめん ウーパ！
She's a good girl.
（ミァ）あの子 いい子だもん
I can't do it.
（フシ）できない！
（３人）あっ
Let's run!
（ウーロイ）逃げるぞ
（トナリ）うん
（ウーロイ）おっ
（トナリ･ウーロイ）ああ…
I'll take care of it. Go without me.
俺に任せて先に行け
え？
Go to their nest, Sandel!
ヤツらの巣に行くんだ！
サンデル！
Right.
はい！
行きましょう トナリさん
Let's go, Tonari-san.
I don't want to.
イヤだ ウーロイ…
Uroy...
No!
（サンデル）うっ… うう…
（トナリ）ミァ…
We're screwed.
もう… 無理か
ぐっ…
（フシ）あっ
Fushi! Turn small!
フシ！　小さくなれ！
Uroy!
ウーロイ
Hurry!
早く！
Please!
頼む リガード！
Ligard!
（フシの叫び声）
It's all right, Fushi.
（ウーロイ）大丈夫だぜ フシ
Even if I die,
俺が死んでも…
I'll have fun in the
paradise of the afterlife.
あの世の楽園で…
楽しく やるさ
Right, Oopa, Mia?
なっ ウーパ… ミァ…
Yeah.
（ミァ）うん
♪～
～♪
Preview
The Nokkers control the dead.
（観察者）死者を操るノッカー
The children cry for their
now-unrecognizable friends.
変わり果てた仲間を思い
涙する子供たち
As Fushi cowers, Hayase forces
him to make a decision.
思わず ひるむフシに
ハヤセは決断を迫る
And Tonari is about to choose
her own fate with her own hands.
そしてトナリは
自らの手で
運命を選ぼうとしていた
Wandering Rage